# Nhat K. (James) Nguyen

### ReactJS Full Stack Software Engineer (Frontend Focused)







### **Contact Information**

### **Address**

**Sydney NSW** 

#### **Phone**

(+61) 416 851 646

#### **Email**

kimnhat98@gmail.com

### **Key Skills**

- JavaScript Development Frameworks (ReactJS, NodeJS, NextJS, Redux, React Native)
- Full-stack Web Development (HTML5, ES6 / JavaScript, jQuery, CSS3, Bootstrap, SASS / LESS)
- Backend & Database Deployment (MongoDB, GraphQL, AWS, RESTful API, Axios, Express, Apollo)
- Test Driven Development (Jest, Enzyme, React Testing Library)
- DevOps (npm, Docker, Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, Jira, Confluence, Microsoft Azure)
- Mobile App Development (Mobile Responsive Design, PWA, React Native)
- Others (SEO, Figma design tool)

### Languages

English Fluent
Vietnamese Native

### **Summary**

I am a mid-level full stack React developer currently based in Australia that looking for Australian industry placements. I have 3+ years of commercial experience in software development & design through various projects I participated in the past (from 2019 to 2022) including: developing full-stack applications, redesigning, and improving UIs and enhancing software's components and visuals, etc.

I graduated Bachelor of Computer Science at University of Wollongong in late 2019. While I tackled many subjects within 3 full years in university (from 2017 to 2019), I have educated and achieved multiple skills including numerous programming languages, software project management and research. Thus, those have given me the necessary foundation to pursue my current career path as well as to understand what to be expected in a professional environment.

Additionally, as I was assigned many tasks and requests that were mostly frontend-based and/or UI-based throughout my career, I have a very strong passion for frontend and UI/UX development.

### **Work Experience**

Frontend Developer @ LifeByte Systems (March 2022 - present)

### Working as a frontend developer at LifeByte Systems:

- Collaborating with a range of team members and stakeholders.
- Developing new user-facing features and building reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Ensuring the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs.
- Validating all the user input before submission to the backend.
- Optimising the delivery of code and assets that mobile and browser responsive.

Web Developer @ Al Talent (April 2021 – November 2021)

### Participated in a few projects developing React/TypeScript software:

Worked in a collaborative and agile team to develop and structure
 JavaScript applications and RESTful Web APIs for the software.

- Identified mobile strategies and designed mobile responsive app for multiple operating systems.
- Designed, assisted and developed software's visualisations in accordance with UI/UX theories.
- Deployed and tested services with a focus on performance and scalability.

### Freelance Web Developer @ Toptal (April 2020 – April 2021)

### Contributed in freelance projects designing and developing web applications:

- Developed and maintained elements for several HTML and ReactJS applications.
- Took clients' requests of designing/redesigning the apps' frontend & UI and update those components accordingly.

### Software Engineer Intern @ CSIRO Data61 (November 2019 – February 2020)

### Participated in one of CSIRO Data61's IT projects for the interns:

- Researched and learnt about Zero-Knowledge Proof (ZKP) concepts;
   experimented and tested the libraries supporting ZKP.
- Developed a prototype in C++ programming language of a scenario based ZKP verification system via Linux OS.
- Presented the built prototype to the CSIRO Data61 researchers;
   documented and published the prototype to GitHub.

### Project Lead Developer @ University of Wollongong (March 2019 – December 2019)

### Led a group project developing a 'Travel Organiser' web application:

- Distributed and managed the work for all team members to complete building the web application which met the project requirements.
- Programmed the app's backend code using PHP, SQL and JSON.
- Assisted other team members in improving the frontend development.
- Learnt more about working with clients and software project management in general.

### **Education**

## Bachelor's Degree @ University of Wollongong (February 2017 – December 2019)

### **Graduated Bachelor of Computer Science (Dean's Scholar):**

- Finished Bachelor's degree with Distinction; achieved high marks in many subjects of which include software development projects as a team leading project manager and/or project developer.
- Studied the Cybersecurity major which educated and assisted students to interact with data flow and data control via Linux OS.
- Researched on 5G technologies in the 'Dean's Scholar Research Project' as a project within the Dean's Scholar program.

### **Certificates**

IELTS Certificate (Academic)
(April 2019)

Overall Score: 7.0

Writing 5.5 – Reading 6.5 – Listening 8.5 – Speaking 8.0

### References

Manny Se – Senior Cloud Platform Engineer @ Telstra

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mannyse